<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj">
		<text>9x18 mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_s">
		<text>9x18 FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_descr">
		<text>A basic FMJ 9x18 mm round. Provides good stopping power against soft targets. Suitable for the Makarov PM, Makarov PB/6P9 and Fort-12 pistols.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm">
		<text>9x18 mm +P+ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_s">
		<text>9x18 +P+</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_descr">
		<text>This round contains a bullet with enhanced stopping power. Ineffective against armored targets. Suitable for the Makarov PM, Makarov PB/6P9 and Fort-12 pistols.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj">
		<text>9x19 mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_s">
		<text>9x19 FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_descr">
		<text>A basic FMJ 9x19 mm round. Ineffective against armored targets. Suitable for the Walther P99, FN Browning High-Power and Beretta 92FS pistols, as well as the H&amp;K MP5 A3 submachine gun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp">
		<text>9x19 mm PBP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_s">
		<text>9x19 PBP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_descr">
		<text>A powerful 9x19 mm round with a hollow point bullet. Ineffective against armored targets. Suitable for the Walther P99, FN Browning High-Power and Beretta 92FS pistols, as well as the H&amp;K MP5 A3 submachine gun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
		<text>.45 ACP FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_s">
		<text>.45 ACP FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_descr">
		<text>A basic FMJ .45 caliber round. Suitable for the Colt M1911 and SIG Sauer P220 pistols.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
		<text>.45 ACP Hydra-Shok rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_s">
		<text>.45 ACP Hydra-Shok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_descr">
		<text>A Hydra-Shok round with improved characteristics for the Colt M1911 and SIG Sauer P220 pistols. The Hydra-Shok comes with a hollow point bullet which provides good stopping power.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
		<text>5.45x39 mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_s">
		<text>5.45x39 FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_descr">
		<text>A standard round for assault rifles of the Warsaw Pact countries. Suitable for the AKS-74U, AKS-74 and AN-94 Abakan assault rifles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap">
		<text>5.45x39 mm BP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_s">
		<text>5.45x39 BP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_descr">
		<text>An armor-piercing round for assault rifles of the Warsaw Pact countries. Suitable for the AKS-74U, AKS-74 and AN-94 Abakan assault rifles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
		<text>5.56x45 mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_s">
		<text>5.56x45 FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_descr">
		<text>A standard issue NATO round widely known under its Belgian SS109 index. Suitable for the Enfield L85 A1, Z-M LR-300 ML, SIG SG 550, H&amp;K G36 and FN F2000 assault rifles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap">
		<text>5.56x45 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_s">
		<text>5.56x45 AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_descr">
		<text>An armor-piercing round for the Enfield L85 A1, Z-M LR-300 ML, SIG SG 550, H&amp;K G36 and FN F2000 assault rifles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9">
		<text>9x39 mm PAB-9 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_s">
		<text>9x39 PAB-9</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_descr">
		<text>A cheap general-purpose round. Despite a subsonic velocity, it provides considerable stopping power. Used with the OTs-14 “Groza” and AS “Val” assault rifles, as well as the VSS “Vintorez” special-purpose sniper rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-ap">
		<text>9x39 mm SP-6 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-ap_s">
		<text>9x39 SP-6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
		<text>7.62x54 mmR 7N14 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_s">
		<text>7.62x54 7N14</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_descr">
		<text>A 7.62-caliber high precision armor-piercing sniper round. Used with the SVD and SVU sniper rifles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap">
		<text>7.62x54 mmR AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_s">
		<text>7.62x54 AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_descr">
		<text>A 7.62-caliber armor-piercing sniper round. Used with the SVD and SVU sniper rifles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-buck">
		<text>12x70 buckshot shells</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-buck_s">
		<text>12x70 buck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-buck_descr">
		<text>A standard 12-caliber shell filled with 6 mm shot. Highly lethal at close range. Used with hunting shotguns, sawn-offs, pump-action shotguns and semi-automatic shotguns.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan">
		<text>12x76 slug shells</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_s">
		<text>12x76 slug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_descr">
		<text>This heavy slug shell is normally used for hunting big game, but is also suitable for other purposes. Instead of piercing, its heavy slug simply crushes through armor. Used with hunting shotguns, sawn-offs, pump-action shotguns and semi-automatic shotguns.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-dart">
		<text>12x76 dart shells</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-dart_s">
		<text>12x76 dart</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-dart_descr">
		<text>A dart shell. Its fins add stability, resulting in increased accuracy. The massive steel body of the bullet can penetrate any body armor. Used with hunting shotguns, sawn-offs, pump-action shotguns and semi-automatic shotguns.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-gauss">
		<text>Accumulators</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-gauss_descr">
		<text>High-capacity energy cells. Used to power a prototype of the EM1 electromagnetic rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-m209">
		<text>M209 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-m209_s">
		<text>M209</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-m209_descr">
		<text>A grenade used with the M203 under-barrel grenade launcher and the FN F2000 integrated grenade launcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25">
		<text>VOG-25 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25_s">
		<text>VOG-25</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25_descr">
		<text>A standard grenade for the GP-25 “Kastyor” under-barrel grenade launcher, the integrated under-barrel attachment for the OTs-14 “Groza”, and the RG-6 revolver-type grenade launcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-og-7b">
		<text>OG-7V rocket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-og-7b_s">
		<text>OG-7V</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-og-7b_descr">
		<text>A fragmentation warhead for the RPG-7. Equally effective against soft targets and lightly armored vehicles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_f1">
		<text>F1 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_f1_descr">
		<text>A defensive hand grenade, with fragments capable of piercing standard issue body armor. Its shock waves have a 10-meter blast radius.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_rgd5">
		<text>RGD-5 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_rgd5_descr">
		<text>An offensive hand grenade with a small radius of fragmentation damage. Its shock waves have an 8-meter blast radius.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_smoke">
		<text>Smoke grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_smoke_descr">
		<text>A smoke hand grenade, used to put up smokescreens. Lasts for 10 seconds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher">
		<text>GP-25 “Kastyor”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher_descr">
		<text>An under-barrel grenade launcher for assault rifles made in Warsaw Pact countries. Uses VOG-25 ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher_m203">
		<text>M203</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher_m203_descr">
		<text>An under-barrel grenade launcher for NATO rifles. Uses M209 ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope">
		<text>PSO-1 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_descr">
		<text>A very common Soviet-made optical scope. Attached to weapons by means of a dovetail mount, which is standard in Warsaw Pact countries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat">
		<text>SUSAT scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_descr">
		<text>A 4x optical scope made in NATO countries. Attached to weapons by means of the NATO-standard Picatinny rail.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_silencer">
		<text>Silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_silencer_descr">
		<text>An effective silencer, assembled by some of the Zone’s craftsmen. Comes with a set of adapters for weapons of all calibers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pm">
		<text>Makarov PM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pm_descr">
		<text>This Soviet legacy is the most common pistol in the Zone. While reliable and cheap, its drawbacks are its small magazine and poor precision. Used as a primary weapon by many rookies, this pistol uses 9x18 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pb">
		<text>Makarov PB/6P9</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pb_descr">
		<text>A pistol with an integrated silencer, formerly used by the Soviet Spetsnaz. Morally obsolete, but potentially effective in the right hands. Uses 9x18 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fort">
		<text>Fort-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fort_descr">
		<text>A Ukrainian-made police pistol. Provides higher accuracy, better ergonomics and a larger magazine than the Makarov at the cost of reliability. Uses 9x18 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_beretta">
		<text>Beretta 92FS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_beretta_descr">
		<text>The Beretta 92FS is in service with the US armed forces and police, as well as various military and law enforcement organizations worldwide. The pistol enjoys similar popularity with members of the underworld, thanks to its power and magazine capacity. Uses 9x19 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_walther">
		<text>Walther P99</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_walther_descr">
		<text>An excellent German-made pistol with high reliability, good accuracy and a large magazine - especially in this model, which uses the 9-mm Parabellum round. Uses 9x19 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_hpsa">
		<text>FN Browning High-Power</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_hpsa_descr">
		<text>The Browning deserves its reputation as one of the best handguns of the 20th century. Reliable, powerful and precise, it holds up to 13 9x19 mm rounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911">
		<text>Colt M1911</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_descr">
		<text>This classic semi-automatic Colt, which passed all the major armed conflicts of the 20th century with flying colors, entered the new millennium with confidence. Its mediocre magazine capacity is largely compensated by the hard-hitting .45 ammo it uses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220">
		<text>SIG Sauer P220</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220_descr">
		<text>This model, designed way back in 1975, is still popular all over the world. Although its magazine is relatively small, the weapon mechanism functions like a Swiss watch. Its other advantage is the powerful .45-caliber Colt ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_usp">
		<text>H&amp;K USP 45 Compact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_usp_descr">
		<text>This trustworthy weapon boasts German quality and reliability. The compact short-range weapon is especially popular with the Zone’s veterans. Uses .45 ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_eagle">
		<text>IMI Desert Eagle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_eagle_descr">
		<text>The true gun of true heroes - bulky, heavy and highly lethal. Its limited use in the Zone can be attributed to its price, size, and a shortage of elephants to hunt. Uses .45 ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5">
		<text>H&amp;K MP5 A3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5_descr">
		<text>Over the last few decades of the 20th century, the H&amp;K MP5 A3, one of the best submachine guns around, was in service with special armed forces and police units worldwide. After being gradually replaced with newer models, it was frequently spotted on the black market, from where it eventually made its way to the Zone in large quantities. Uses 9x19 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u">
		<text>AKS-74U</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_descr">
		<text>Despite being similar to submachine guns in size and weight, this weapon is classified as an assault rifle due to its mechanism and ammo. Notable for its small size (an extremely useful feature for fighting in urban environments) and high armor-penetration capacity, its main drawbacks are its short effective range and a tendency to overheat quickly from burst fire. Uses 5.45x39 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74">
		<text>AKS-74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_descr">
		<text>This weapon, designed in 1974, uses 5.45x39 mm ammo. It is a simple and reliable weapon, although its low cost of production somewhat compromised its ease of use and accuracy. In the Zone it is the main weapon of the military and many lone stalkers. Uses 5.45x39 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_abakan">
		<text>AN-94 Abakan</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_abakan_descr">
		<text>A 1996 model based on the AK-47. Designed for accurate short-burst fire. Uses 5.45x39 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_l85">
		<text>Enfield L85 A1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_l85_descr">
		<text>After the British army replaced this rifle with a newer model, large quantities of it emerged on the black market and then in the Zone. The rifle’s main advantages are its built-in 1.8x scope and high first-shot accuracy. However, accuracy decreases significantly when firing in bursts, while the rifle’s basic internal mechanisms are somewhat unreliable. Uses 5.56x45 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_lr300">
		<text>Z-M LR-300 ML</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_lr300_descr">
		<text>A new step in the development of the famous M-16 family. Thanks to an exceptionally smooth release, good ergonomics and satisfactory weight, this rifle facilitates high firing accuracy. However, it is prone to catching dirt, which may lower its effectiveness in field conditions. Uses 5.56x45 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550">
		<text>SIG SG 550</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_descr">
		<text>A relatively new Swiss-made assault rifle which uses the NATO round. The weapon’s precision, soft release and high reliability account for its global popularity. Uses 5.56x45 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_g36">
		<text>H&amp;K G36</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_g36_descr">
		<text>This German-made assault rifle is a first-rate example of a modern weapon - lightweight, reliable and ergonomic. Uses 5.56x45 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fn2000">
		<text>FN F2000</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fn2000_descr">
		<text>This assault rifle features a computerized fire control system and a 40-mm grenade launcher. Uses 5.56x45 mm ammo and M209 grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_groza">
		<text>OTs-14-4A “Groza”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_groza_descr">
		<text>This assault rifle, combined with a grenade launcher, is a great solution for the Zone’s challenges: a compact, reliable and powerful all-purpose weapon. Particularly popular with military stalkers. Uses 9x39 mm ammo and VOG-25 grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_val">
		<text>AS “Val”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_val_descr">
		<text>A modified version of the silent VSS “Vintorez” sniper rifle, the AS “Val” features a folding stock, is capable of burst fire and has a larger magazine. Initially intended for use by special units in assault operations that require silent, flashless fire. Uses 9x39 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez">
		<text>VSS “Vintorez”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez_descr">
		<text>A sniper rifle purpose-built for silent, flashless sniping and equipped with an integrated silencer. Highly rated by many stalkers despite its small magazine. Uses 9x39 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svd">
		<text>SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svd_descr">
		<text>A weapon that has been widely used in all Soviet and Russian military operations since the 1960s. Has earned its reputation for exceptional reliability and ease of use. Uses 7.62 7H14 ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svu">
		<text>SVU</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svu_descr">
		<text>A modernized sniper rifle in a compact bullpup design. Its faster precision fire and lightweight design have earned it the admiration of countless stalkers. Uses 7.62 7H14 ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_rp">
		<text>PKM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_rp_descr">
		<text>Despite its weight and low precision, this light machine gun has found admirers in the Zone. Used primarily to fight off superior enemy forces or clear out mutant lairs. Uses 7.62 PP ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_bm16">
		<text>Sawn-off TOZ-66</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_bm16_descr">
		<text>A sawn-off hunting shotgun with two side-by-side barrels. While much lighter and more compact than a full shotgun, it is only effective at close range. One of the most popular weapons among rookie stalkers. Uses 12x70 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34">
		<text>TOZ-34</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_descr">
		<text>A very common and utterly unremarkable over-and-under hunting shotgun. Used mostly by rookies on the outskirts of the Zone. Uses 12x70 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12">
		<text>Franchi SPAS-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12_descr">
		<text>The SPAS-12 smoothbore semi-automatic shotgun was designed in the late 1970s as an all-purpose weapon for the police and army assault troops. While highly reliable and flexible it is quite bulky, complex and expensive. Probably the best close-range weapon in the Zone. Uses 12x70 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300">
		<text>Mossberg Maverick 88</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300_descr">
		<text>An extremely reliable American-made smoothbore pump-action shotgun designed for combat in the harshest of environments. All of its parts are coated with an anticorrosion compound. Uses 12x70 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_rpg7">
		<text>RPG-7</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_rpg7_descr">
		<text>This rocket launcher from the 1960s made its way into the Zone from army depots. Although its huge size and weight make it an unlikely weapon for a stalker it can be downright irreplaceable for certain jobs. Uses OG-7V grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_rg6">
		<text>RG-6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_rg6_descr">
		<text>This revolver grenade launcher is indispensable when clearing large areas of mutants, attacking well-defended fixed targets, or fighting particularly tough monsters. Uses VOG-25 grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_gauss">
		<text>EM1 Rifle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_gauss_descr">
		<text>An experimental electromagnetic rifle used for incapacitating electronic devices from a distance. Ineffective against live targets. Powered by accumulator batteries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5_m1">
		<text>MP5 A3 Mk2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5_m1_descr">
		<text>A modified version of the MP5 A3 submachine gun. Thanks to better component alignment, this weapon has higher muzzle velocity. Uses 9x19 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_hpsa_m1">
		<text>HPSA-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_hpsa_m1_descr">
		<text>This weapon is a modified version of the Browning High-Power pistol for use in harsh climates. The virtually foolproof handgun uses 9x19 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fort_m1">
		<text>Fort-15</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fort_m1_descr">
		<text>The Fort-15 has a larger magazine than the basic model. Uses 9x18 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_m1">
		<text>AKS-74M</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_m1_descr">
		<text>This is a modernized version of the AKS-74 assault rifle. An advanced design boosts its rate of fire by 100 rounds per minute. Some design elements were removed to lighten the barrel, which renders optical scopes unusable. Uses 5.45x39 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_eagle_m1">
		<text>Big Ben</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_eagle_m1_descr">
		<text>A true Goliath among pistols. Its already lengthy barrel is additionally extended with a special permanent attachment. Provides outstanding stopping power and uses .45-caliber ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_m1">
		<text>SIG SG 550/5.45</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_m1_descr">
		<text>Some crafty folk have modified the SIG SG 550 to work with the Soviet round, which is more common in the Zone, all the while retaining the rifle’s ability to use any of the base model’s modifications. Uses 5.45x39 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_abakan_m1">
		<text>Silenced AN-94</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_abakan_m1_descr">
		<text>A silent version of the AN-94 Abakan. The weapon has a craftily silencer-extended barrel, which increases accuracy, while still retaining all the advantages of an assault rifle. Uses 5.45x39 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300_m1">
		<text>Freedom Maverick 88</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300_m1_descr">
		<text>Unlike most shotguns, this one has a rifled bore. This makes shot and dart fire impossible, but significantly increases precision when firing slugs. Uses only 12x76 slug ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez_m1">
		<text>Val Vintorez</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez_m1_descr">
		<text>A hybrid version that combines the advantages of both models, resulting in a 20-round magazine and very accurate automatic fire. The rifle’s 2x scope is tailored for short-range use. Uses 9x39 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12_m2">
		<text>Duty SPAS-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12_m2_descr">
		<text>The Duty SPAS-12 semi-automatic shotgun is made only in Duty workshops, purpose-built for fighting swarms of monsters. An improved cartridge-feed mechanism ensures a better rate of fire and amazing groupings when using shot ammo. An extended magazine holds up to 10 12x70 mm rounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_lr300_m1">
		<text>Sniper LR-300 ML</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_lr300_m1_descr">
		<text>This weapon is an exceptional piece of workmanship, customized for its owner. The design sacrifices rate of fire for precision, so if you need to hit the same exact spot 10 times in 10 seconds - this is the weapon for you. Uses 5.56x45 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_l85_m1">
		<text>Sniper L85</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_l85_m1_descr">
		<text>A sniper version of the L85 assault rifle. Its extended barrel ensures greater muzzle velocity, thereby flattening bullet trajectory and allowing for accurate fire at greater distances. Uses 5.56x45 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fn2000_m1">
		<text>FN F2000 S</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fn2000_m1_descr">
		<text>A modernized version of the FN2000 with an emphasis on accurate burst fire. The under-barrel grenade launcher is fitted with a gravitational bullet stabilizer resulting in significantly lower dispersion. The drawback of this modification is that it renders the grenade launcher unusable. Uses 5.56x45 mm ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svu_m1">
		<text>SVU Mk2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svu_m1_descr">
		<text>This automatic version of the SVU has much softer recoil, which allows for faster accurate fire. Uses 7.62 7H14 ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_groza_m1">
		<text>Sniper OTs-14</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_groza_m1_descr">
		<text>A sniper prototype of the OTs-14 “Groza” assault rifle. This balanced weapon is good for precision and automatic fire. The under-barrel grenade launcher can also come in handy. Uses 9x39 mm ammo and VOG-25 grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-ap_descr">
		<text>An armor-piercing 9x39 mm round. Despite a subsonic velocity, it provides considerable stopping power thanks to its caliber. The special bullet design allows it to penetrate most body armor. Used with the OTs-14 “Groza” and AS “Val” assault rifles, as well as the VSS “Vintorez” special-purpose sniper rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_knife">
		<text>Knife</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo_minigame_descr">
		<text>Ammo with markings specific to the shooting gallery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo_minigame_name">
		<text>Shooting gallery ammo</text>
	</string>
</string_table>